WAYNE STARR

wes7817@g.rit.edu - (970) 366-2530

PROFILE

Third Year Software Engineering Student at Rochester Institute of Technology with 3.5 years of leadership experience from Air Force ROTC. Excels at Java, C#, JavaScript, Ruby, Visual Basic, Python, C++, and C application development, and always willing to learn.

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology

Rochester, NY | 3.80 GPA | Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering | 2011-Present

Courses: Software Engineering, Engr Fund Comp Systems, Personal Software Engr, Intro To Cs Theory, Operating Systems I, Eng Of Software Subsys, Eng of Concur Distrib SW Sys, Software Testing, Human Centered Regs and Design

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, C#, JavaScript, Ruby, Visual Basic, Python, C++, C, HTML, CSS

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Mac OS X

Development Software: Microsoft Visual Studio, Eclipse, Android Studio, Microsoft Visio

Software: Microsoft Office Suite

PROJECTS

- Developing an Android app to plug into DuckDuckGo's Instant Answer API in my free time
- Implemented a new interface for class search and enrollment written in Angular.js as part of the Student IT Office, working with external customers around campus as well as ITS on campus.
- Team lead for a C# based budget tracking software complete with reports, and a fluid user interface. Worked to hold meetings, perform usability testing, and define necessary changes.

EXPERIENCE

Student IT Office, Rochester New York

Web Developer | Jan 2014 - May 2014, Sep 2014 - Present

- Design, Develop, Test, Deploy, and Maintain enterprise-level web apps for RIT
- Work with a cross-functional team to improve business, development, and design processes

Microsoft, Seattle Washington

Software Developer in Test (Intern) | Jun 2014 – Aug 2014

- Work with Big Data to discover insights to find ways of improving log scraping for Bing
- Create dynamic reports on data using Excel, and SharePoint

HONORS/ACTIVITIES

- RIT Presidential Scholarship recipient
- 3.5 years leadership experience in Air Force Reserve Officer Training Corps
- 2.5 years in Arnold Air Society with 12 months as Area 01 Financial Management Officer
- Placed on Dean's List all 6 academic quarters
- Enjoy mountain biking, video gaming, snowshoeing, working on cars and off-roading